Black Men Loving Black Men
Tongues Untied is a documentary film directed by Marlon Riggs.
Marlon Riggs, with assistance from other gay Black men, especially poet Essex
Hemphill, celebrates Black men loving Black men as a revolutionary act.
The film intercuts footage of Hemphill reciting his poetry, Riggs telling the story of his growing up, scenes of men in social intercourse and dance, and various comic
riffs, including a visit to the "Institute of Snap!thology," where men take lessons in how to snap their fingers: the sling snap, the point snap, the diva snap.
Self, played by Marlon Riggs.
Self - Poetry Performance, played by Essex Hemphill.
Self, played by Brian Freeman.
Self, played by Michael Bell.
Self, played by Willi Ninja.
Self, played by Kerrigan Black.
A shot-on-video (SOV) film, also known as a shot-on-VHS film or a camcorder film, is a film shot using
camcorders and consumer-grade equipment, as opposed to film stock or high-end digital movie cameras.
The film explores themes of lgbt, black lgbt, african american man.